# Ziad Saab - Software Developer & Instructor

I've been a software developer for over fifteen years. My passion lies around creating simple and elegant solutions to real problems. I also enjoy teaching and mentoring on the subject of Software Development. I'm always looking to skill up and be challenged.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Self-Employed, World** — Software Developer

JUNE 2001 - PRESENT

- I do business development through client prospecting and networking
- I analyze customers' needs to help them build a product development strategy
- I work with clients to define their product roadmap, milestones, and iterations
- I implement Software Development processes and tooling where needed

### DecodeMTL, Montréal - Co-Founder and Instructor

AUGUST 2014 - DECEMBER 2017

- I co-founded Montreal's first web development bootcamp, DecodeMTL
- I created an eight-week full-stack web development curriculum aimed at novice developers
- I hired and managed mentors to help the students during their time with us

#### **EDUCATION**

McGill University, Montréal - B.Sc., Computer Science

## **PROJECTS**

#### Udacity SQL Nanodegree - Instructor and Course Designer

SPRING 2019

- Built an online SQL course + Postgres-based project with Udactity
- Produced the course content videos, audio, slides, examples, quizzes, final project
- Received praise from Udacity for being one of the top-rated instructors on the platform

#### Wellify - Mentoring and Software Architecture

2020 - PRESENT

- Moved a no-SSR, React-based e-commerce project to Next.js + Firebase, deployed on Vercel
- Implemented Stripe, Stripe Connect, Zoom, and other APIs
- Mentored junior developers on software and security best-practices

#### Creative Queue - Product Development, Software Architecture and Development

SPRING 2020

- Advised my client on building a proper MVP for a collaborative commercial photo app
- Architected a real-time app using React, Firebase, TypeScript, and MobX in mono-repo format
- Received constant praise from my client for the quality of my work and my communication skills